William Burn Letters
William Burn Letters
1797-1799
Burn, William.
1 folder (SC)
Letters from a British Army officer in India to James Miller, his stockbroker and friend, in Calcutta.
149184
Biographical History
Captain (later Lt. Colonel) William Burn was a British Army officer stationed in India during the late 18th century.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William Burn Letters contains correspondence between William Burn in India and his stockbroker and friend, James Miller, in Calcutta, painting an interesting picture of an army officer's life during the British conquest of India. Burn describes the bloody battles between the Moslem followers of the Tartar and the Sikhs, the pomp and the parades, the diplomatic maneuverings between the British and the Indian princes, and the method of raising money by the British Government and British East India Company for the Indian campaign by public subscription. Burn also tells of his efforts to support his children and himself on an officer's pay, his desire for promotion, his worries about his future retirement on half-pay, and his attempts to supplement his income by buying Lottery tickets and trying to make shrewd investments.
Subject and Genre Headings
Burn, William.; Miller, James.; Great Britain. -- Army -- Officers -- Correspondence.; Correspondence.; Military history
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 7 Feb 1797, 4 pages (Sc 230)
  - 22 Feb 1797, 3 pages (Sc 230)
  - 04 Mar 1797, 1 page (Sc 230)
  - 26 Sep 1797, 2 pages (Sc 230)
  - 01 Oct 1797, 4 pages (Sc 230)
  - 13 Dec 1797, 2 pages (Sc 230)
  - 01 Jan 1798, 10 Jan 1798, 11 Jan 1798, 4 pages (Sc 230)
  - 13 Jan 1798, 2 pages (Sc 230)
  - 20 Jan 1798, 3 pages (Sc 230)
  - 30 Jan 1798, 4 pages (Sc 230)
  - 13 Feb 1798, 4 pages (Sc 230)
  - 17 Feb 1798, 3 pages (Sc 230)
  - 13 Jun 1798, 25 Jun 1798, 2 pages (Sc 230)
  - 04 Jul 1798, 2 pages (Sc 230)
  - 18 Aug 1798, 4 pages (Sc 230)
  - 20 Aug 1798, 3 pages (Sc 230)
  - 30 Aug 1798, 3 pages (Sc 230)
  - 11 Sep 1798, 4 pages (Sc 230)
  - 07 Oct 1798, 3 pages (Sc 230)
  - 25 Oct 1798, 3 pages (Sc 230)
  - 27 Nov 1798, 2 pages (Sc 230)
  - 01 Dec 1798, 16 Dec 1798, 3 pages (Sc 230)
  - 19 Jan 1799, 31 Jan 1799, 3 pages (Sc 230)
  - 22 Jan 1799, 3 pages (Sc 230)